Balram Ingale

Pune , Maharashtra / +918412938177

balramingale841@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/balramingale

Personal Portfolio: - Balram - Personal Portfolio (balramingale.netlify.app)

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY (Test Automation Eng Analyst)

I am currently working in **Accenture** as **Test Automation Eng Analyst** and before I worked in **Cognizant Technology Solution** as **Associate** .I have total **3 years** of experience in Automation Testing-Selenium with Java upto present.

EXPERIENCE

Test Automation Eng Analyst

Pune, Maharashtra

(Aug 2024 – Present)

Accenture (VOIS Client)

- 1. Skilled in Web application automation using Selenium with Java, Including the implementation of Selenium Keyword-Driven frameworks(SKDF) and BDD framework.
- 2. Experience in Agile methodology using JIRA
- 3. Understanding of STLC & Defect Life Cycle.
- **4.** Knowledge & Completed hands-on of API testing using Rest Assured.
- **5.** Completed Handson of Playwright Automation using JavaScript.

Associate Pune, Maharashtra

(Dec 2021-Apr2024)

Cognizant Technology Solution (Comcast Client)

- 1. Proficient in Web application automation using **Selenium Webdriver (Java)**, Including the implementation of Data-Driven and Hybrid frameworks(TestNG).
- **2.** Skilled in creating, modifying and enhancing manual testcases and test scripts withinthe Selenium WebDriver framework.
- **3.** Experienced in writing XPath expressions and CSS selectors for efficient identification of web elements.
- **4.** Familiarity with **Jenkins**, including job configuration and execution of TestNGtestcases directly from Jenkins.
- **5.** Successfully led the migration from **Jenkins to Concourse**, streamlining testing processes and improving efficiency.
- 6. Proficient in various types of testing, including **regression testing**, **retesting**, **functional testing**, **end-to-end testing and data load testing**.
- 7. Basic understanding of software version control systems, particularly Git.
- **8.** Facilitated **knowledge transfer** session(KT) to onboard new team members, ensuring smooth integration into project workflows.
- **9.** Contributed to the interview process for potential new team members, evaluating candidate qualification and fit for the team.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

Project :-Comcast (Telecommunication Domain) –(Dec2021-Apr2024)

- 1. Conducted comprehensive requirement analysis to ensure clear understanding.
- 2. Developed, modified and enhanced manual test cases and test scripts within the Selenium WebDriver framework to ensure thorough testing coverage.
- 3. Analyzed failures in Jenkins and performed **automation maintenance** task in Jenkins/ Concourse CI to optimize testexecution.
- 4. Executed functional and regression testing to validate system functionality.
- 5. Collaborated with developers in **defect/bug review sessions** to identify and resolve isues efficiently.
- 6. Provided detailed testing issue reports and result to project managers for informed decision-making.
- 7. Supported sanity and regression testing in production environments during **rolling deployments** to maintain system integrity.
- 8. Actively participated in **daily scrum calls, standup meetings, and sprint planning sessions** to ensure alignments with project goals and timeline

Project :-Vodaphone Portugal VOIS (Telecommunication Domain) –(Aug2024-till)

- 1. Developed, modified and enhanced manual test cases and test scripts within the SKDF Selenium Keyword-Driven Framework.
- 2. Working on Siebel CRM application.
- 3. Actively participated in **daily scrum calls, standup meetings, and sprint planning sessions** to ensure alignments with project goals and timeline
- 4. Experienced in writing XPath expressions and CSS selectors for efficient identification of web elements.

EDUCATION

BE - Electrical Engineering

July 2018 - July

P.E.S Modern College of Engg, Pune MH

of Engg, Pune MH 8.9 CGPA

SKILLS

Intermediate in: Automation Testing using Selenium with Java, API Testing, CI-CD using Jenkins & Concourse, Selenium Keyword-Driven Framework, BDD Cucumber framework, TestNG Hybrid Framework, Data Driven Framework, Rally, Jira, STLC, SDLC, Defect life cycle, Bug Tracking, Agile methodology, GIT, Microsoft 365, Cypress & Playwright automation using JavaScript, Xpath & CSS, HTML, CSS, Maven, Automation Maintenance, Postman API testing, ChatGPT AI (Prompt)

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Generative AI Fundamentals	2024
Cognizant Technology Solutions Corporation	
Selenium Webdriver Masterclass for Automation Testing Udemy	2024
Learn Devops : CI-CD with Jenkins Udemy	2023
Azure Fundamentals(AZ-900) Microsoft	2023
Learn Cucumber BDD with Java Masterclass selenium framework. Udemy	2024
	2024

HONORS & AWARDS

Cognizant Cheers Award

2023

- 1. **Achievement Recognition**: Received Cognizant Cheers Award from manager and senior manager for outstanding contribution.
- 2. **Project Impact**: Recognized for Significant contribution to the completion of Jenkins to Concourse migration project.
- 3. **Efficiency Improvement**: Acknowledged for implementing automation strategies resulting in substantial time saving in testing processes.
- 4. **Team Collaboration**: Demonstrated effective collaboration with cross-functional teams to ensure successful project execution.
- 5. **Quality Enhancement**: Played a key role in enhancing testing efficiency.